Previously on Star Trek:
Strange New Worlds...
Six months nonstop.
I'm just worried the crew
is starting to feel the strain.
We could all use a night off.
Why is everyone obsessed
with me taking breaks?
Work will still be here
in five minutes.
Fine. Let's... relax.
My mind to your mind.
-You and I will remain friends.
-I think so. Spock.
Scotty acts like
every time I steer the ship.
it makes his job harder. So he added endless beeping...
-to make my job harder.
-There's a reason for those lights.
Shut them off. Scotty.
-Frickin' engineers.
-Bloody pilots.
Lieutenant
Erica Ortegas personal log.
Stardate 2011.7.
We're on our way
to the Rodaxian system.
where the captain will be
negotiating a peace treaty
in a civil war.
And it's not exactly
an easy system to fly to.
Which. thank goodness.
is why I'm at the helm.
Lieutenant
Montgomery Scott personal log.
Stardate 2011.7.
As we head through
a fickle region of space.
ship's been needing
round-the-clock maintenance.
Normally I don't complain.
It's just that Beta
and Gamma shifts
got shore leave last month.
while Alpha shift didn't.
Let's face it.
Alpha shift's a big deal.
But. come on. we need
the same break
Beta and Gamma get.
It's wearing on everyone.
The only reason
this region of space
is tricky is because of the way
some people choose to fly.
And that's precisely why
I added the alert system.
Going over my head
to say I exceed parameters
was bad enough.
Installing a warning light
to tell me how to fly?
This feels personal.
It's fine though.
Everything's fine.
Things get bumpy.
you push your way forward.
even if something's in your way.
And she went over my head.
Ignoring the controls.
She-She's taking this too far.
Someone's attitude
has everyone on edge.
She's a know-it-all. arrogant...
Micromanaging. rude...
Constantly trying
to take control...
-Lieutenant.
Uh-oh.
They look like they want
to kill each other.
They're not the only ones.
La'An is itching for a fight.
which Spock is just trying
to stay out of.
Joseph needs to loosen up
even more than you do.
Respectfully. sir.
And don't get me started
on Chapel
and whatever's going on there.
Damn it.
I guess I have just been
thinking about negotiations.
Which I'm going to need
Alpha shift's help with.
And they very much need a break.
Suggestions?
Oh. hey!
I didn't see you there.
Just kidding. I did.
Are you ready
for the time of your life?
Because I'm here
to give that to you.
"Dendru's the name. or you can
call me "your new best friend
on your personal journey
to de-stresstation."
And this...
is the Cesnar Grand.
Thanks to our planet's
one-of-a-kind
intoxicating atmosphere.
each visitor experiences
a one-of-a-kind.
customized journey
that will provide
exactly what they need
to relax.
Speaking of relaxing...
This is a place to say
"no way" to those icky parts
of your daily life.
Even technology!
That's right.
This is a tech-free zone.
The only focus here
is living your best life!
Atmospheric effects
harmlessly wear off
shortly after departure.
Arrival on the planet is
an explicit release
of all liabilities on the part
of Cesnar Grand
or its employees.
Alpha crew
is taking shore leave.
And the Rodaxian peace talks?
We have two weeks before we land
in their region.
And the resort planet's directly
on our path.
Nothing against vacations.
but the Rodaxians
are very specific
in how they like
to be spoken to.
I was hoping
we would use this time
to review
the formal kickoff speech.
And I was worried
about having enough time
to do all the ship repairs
before negotiations. too.
A pit stop sounds great to me.
A break is crucial to take
the edge off
before the negotiations.
A day or two on Cesnar
and you'll all still have
a week to work after that.
The spokesperson said
"intoxicating atmosphere."
-Is it safe?
-Completely.
Anyone who goes
will feel naturally inebriated
by the planetary gases.
The effect is different
for each person.
and it wears off. like.
an hour after leaving.
I promise you.
this will be
the best shore leave ever.
Can't argue with that.
Do you think we can
survive a week without our tricorders?
They didn't say this
place was mandatory tech-free.
I'll still get some work in.
I brought one as well. Oh!
You know.
it's a thin atmosphere.
-You need to let up on the...
-On the backseat driving?
Is that what you were gonna say?
I was gonna say if you come in
hot. you're gonna land hard.
I'm setting down
on a shuttle storage conveyer.
Pretty much parks itself.
Right. But you still need
to brake.
Whoa!
Great. Now I'll have
to stay and fix that.
Well. that would be a tragedy.
What. did you do that
on purpose?
I didn't.
But if you're thinking
this place better be big enough
for us to get a break
from each other.
I am right there with you.
Christine. how long
until that atmospheric
inebriation kicks in. hmm?
As soon as that door opens.
just count down from ten.
Ten.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven. Six.
-Four.
-Seven.
-Five.
-Six.
Four.
Three.
Four and a half!
Lieutenant!
What are you...
I don't know!
I don't remember anything!
Am I a mugato now?
What's the last thing
you remember?
Uh. shuttle.
You biffed the landing.
Are you drunk?
Why am I not drunk?
Can you just...
Sit down.
On the floor.
Don't touch anything.
So bossy.
Hello! Me again.
-Again?
-A message came for your captain.
It's time-sensitive.
He wasn't in his room.
so I am hoping
that you can deliver it to him.
Can you do that?
Hey. man.
I'm confused.
-Go on.
-Promises were made.
and none of those promises
included a hangover
or missing time.
Sometimes if you're hanging on
to negative emotions.
it can negate or alter
the effects of the atmosphere.
That wasn't in the brochure.
Mm. it was. it was.
It was in the fine print.
Well. actually.
it was in the micro print.
But the fine print
clearly directs you
to read the micro print.
So. really.
it's all quite legally binding.
Tell you what.
after you deliver that.
I promise to fix you up.
And in the meantime.
just remember.
take deep breaths.
Deep breaths. And. you know.
the-the deposit
is nonrefundable.
-What is that?
-A letter.
A piece of paper?
Don't you remember the video?
This is a tech-free zone.
Hence...
You stay here.
Or not.
Or do whatever you're gonna do.
Ooh!
Souvenir.
-Ow. it's sharp.
-Or you can't be left alone.
Of course.
We'll just deliver this note
to the captain.
and he can deal with you.
'Cause there's no way
we're gonna be stuck
with each other on vacation.
Mm.
Space.
The final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its five-year mission:
to explore strange new worlds...
to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
Guess I'll just start at door number one.
Someone has to know
where the captain is.
Stop.
Are you Lieutenant Ortegas
and Lieutenant Scott?
Oh. boy.
I apologize for the mess.
-Is Captain Pike here?
-Not that I am aware of.
-Where's La'An?
-She is on a more spirited journey than my own.
As you can no doubt see.
I am quite incapacitated.
-You are?
-Entirely.
You seem pretty normal.
Do you see James Kirk
in this room?
No...
Unless he's invisible.
Cloaked.
I have been hallucinating
a manifestation of James Kirk.
We've been playing board games.
Wonder what that's all about.
This is fun and all. but do
you know where the captain is?
I need to find him now.
-You appear tense.
-I don't remember
what I did last night.
I have a pounding headache.
And if I want to get
any enjoyment at all out of
this so-called vacation.
I apparently need to deliver
a note to him first.
So. yeah.
tense.
You do not recall
fighting a dragon?
Is that a joke?
I heard you shouting
in the corridor that you
"got the dragon."
I'll add that to my list
of things to figure out.
And Pike is...?
He mentioned Uhura's party.
Two doors south.
Ah. well. there we go.
An actual lead.
Thank you.
Should we order some fries?
Do you think my seeing you here
has deeper meaning?
Deeper than what?
Perhaps a remnant of you was
left behind after our mind meld
and is now filling
an emotional void.
Do you need a hug?
Oh. bring it in here.
Mmm.
Don't even think about it.
My friends.
You're here.
Erica. you were so right.
Relaxation is just so...
relaxing.
I love it. Boop.
-Oh. this is amazing.
-Mm-hmm.
This is amazing.
-Is Pike here? I have to give him something.
-Hmm?
Then I need to stay here
and never leave.
Mm.
Oh! Yeah.
No.
-He's not here.
-Do you know where he is?
Mm. it's not my journey to know.
We're all
on our own journeys here.
Why would my journey
involve breaking my arm
and maybe a dragon?
Chapel mentioned your cast.
Said you didn't want
your arm fixed.
Glutton for pain.
Probably where
all that anger comes from.
I'm not angry.
-Okay.
-You know what?
You stay with Uhura.
I'll find Pike.
Mm.
No. you guys are...
That is so not my vibe
right now. But...
good luck on your journey.
Mmm.
Can you at least
give me something?
-Any idea where Pike might be?
-He...
is... on... his... own...
journey.
Mmm...
Bye. Bring back cookies.
Her hands are so soft.
Scotty.
Scotty. Scotty.
You can't go off on your own.
Since apparently
another task I have
is babysitting
a small grown man.
I am average-sized.
-Mm.
-I'm just following the clues. okay?
-Really want to win the big prize.
-There is no prize.
We're delivering a note
to the captain.
It's not a scavenger hunt.
She's pretty good.
She probably knows
where Pike is.
How are there
so many Klingon power ballads?
And she signed up
to sing 15 in a row.
Warrior's songs.
Friends.
-Doctor.
-Showtime!
Have you...
Have you seen Captain Pike?!
Ooh!
I'll take one of whatever
that is you're making.
No. No. No. he won't.
And you don't work here. Doctor.
What is it?
It's green.
Cool. right?
How did you learn to do that?
I'm just winging it.
When I move my hands.
I'm usually worried
about people's lives.
But now?
It's like Una singing.
Ah. that's cool. man.
Wait. Doctor.
The captain.
Captain?
Hmm?
Hi.
Can I ask you a question?
What would you think
of a face tattoo?
You should get one. Mr. Scott.
You'd look good.
Well. I don't tell this
to everyone.
but I actually have a tattoo.
-On my...
-Stop.
Sir. a message came for you.
Thank you.
You shouldn't do it.
Old-school.
Paper envelope. I like it.
We should get these
for the ship.
Drive Uhura crazy.
So. apparently.
the Rodaxian diplomats
are coming to us.
That's good.
And they'll be here
in approximately
two hours.
We're not meeting them
for two weeks.
Oh. no.
What should we do?
Uh. you...
go get the shuttle.
And then by the time
you come back.
I'll be done
with the horsey thingy on my arm
and then I'll have
everybody rounded up
and ready to go. partner.
Scotty. stay here.
And let you biff
the shuttle again?
Hey. hey. hey.
I like you two
having fun together.
You should keep it going.
You're gonna have to work fast.
You should come to Montana.
This is the worst vacation ever.
Oh. let's do that one.
Tellurite.
-Sexy.
-We can't just take...
Hang on.
Our shuttle's supposed
to be right here.
-Did you move it?
-Why would I move it?
I don't know. Why did you install warning lights?
No one could move it without
the duotronic processing chip.
We gave that to...
an attendant. right?
I kind of remember that.
Do you have it now?
Uh...
Look. whoever has that moved it.
-Hi.
-Oh.
Hey.
Do you know
what happened to our shuttle?
Boxy. Beige-white.
Federation issue.
-I gave the chip to him.
-Me?
Oh.
A few hours ago.
"Whoever has that moved it."
Where'd you put it?
I don't think
I would've taken it.
That doesn't sound like...
I don't remember doing that.
So what now?
We're screwed.
Yeah. that's bad.
The shuttle could be anywhere.
I was thinking
maybe it was cloaked.
-Like Kirk.
-Okay.
I tried to be cool to you...
What does you uncool
to someone look like?
But now my vacation is ruined.
the shuttle is missing.
and the peace talks are blown.
thanks to you.
You're acting like
there's no way to find it.
It's still somewhere.
We just need...
My tricorder.
We could use that as a locator.
Wait. that's somehow actually
a great idea. Where is it?
I left it on the shuttle.
But I do know one person
who would never leave
a tricorder behind.
I'm not giving you my tricorder.
Why not?
Because giving you my tricorder
is not my journey.
You need to follow your journey.
Wait. what if your journey
is our journey?
Ours... uh...
Lieutenant Ortegas and I.
that is...
is to track down a shuttle
together using your tricorder.
Okay.
You two working together.
That does feel like
your journey.
Yep. That's our journey.
Tricorder.
Before I give it to you.
you two need
to clear this energy.
Apologize to each other.
Apologize for what?
Let's just do it.
Erica.
I'm sorry that I...
uh...
doubted you.
-And your turn.
-Okay.
And. Monty. I...
Montgomery. Hate that.
I'm sorry...
I was upset
about your constant
doubting of me.
There.
Don't we all feel
so much better?
-Mm. Great.
-Yep.
Oh.
Come back soon!
You know you want to!
Who wants a shot?!
I got this.
It's my job. Whoa!
Bright.
Ah! I can see the shuttle
through the hotel
security system.
Here. look.
Where'd you go?
Oh. there you are.
What the hell?
It was a security system.
Why would you throw it at me
to show me
-a security system?
-I don't know.
I'm probably not the best
decision-maker right now.
-Understatement.
-Therefore this might not be the best plan.
The security network had
a hub in the central office.
So we go there.
hack into the computer.
track our shuttle. Boom.
Yepper yep.
Exactly.
Can you hack into a computer
right now?
Probably no.
Not a chance. no.
Then we'll get someone who can.
I may not be very useful.
given
my clearly inebriated state.
You know you seem totally fine.
Absurd.
Are you sure you saw a computer?
Because I don't see one.
Yeah. I'm positive.
I think.
Uh...
It is coming from this.
That is a plant.
I believe this is
photosynthetic technology.
I assumed
that was only theoretical.
It's a plant.
Perhaps
I can telepathically link.
What. read the plant's
plant mind?
My mind to your leaves.
My thoughts to your root system.
I can see the security map.
The shuttle is just north.
An area run
by a local gang of thieves.
I would recommend
bringing La'An as muscle.
She has quite a bit
of pent-up energy today.
So she's even scarier?
She is much. much scarier.
The three of us will be fine.
I should not join you.
This is pretty important. Spock.
Mm.
Are you both plants right now?
Um. no.
I should rest.
I mean. maybe I'm a plant.
You're not a plant.
Let's get La'An.
Oh.
Photosynthetic technology?
Nice.
I may know
why I am imagining you.
I've never had what humans
call a "human best friend."
We don't actually call it
a human best friend.
But I think you mean someone
that you can be vulnerable with.
I have many things
I want to talk about.
Fears.
hopes.
dreams.
I believe you are here
so I can share them with you.
Even though
you are in fact not here.
Okay. buddy.
Let's talk.
Weapons are not necessary.
This is a relaxation class.
Was!
Now it's
an Anbo-jyutsu tournament
-to the death!
-Ooh.
Everyone form factions!
Now! Stand up.
-On your feet. On your feet.
-Yeah. I'd bet on the left team.
-Sturdier.
-Feet together.
-Stand up tall.
-I'm grabbing La'An.
You. over there.
Get in line.
-You want some. too? Huh?
-No.
Do you?
-Do you?
-Definitely not.
But I do have
just the job for you.
Bring the stick.
Okay. so we'll go in.
make some threats.
get our shuttle back.
He must be in charge.
Stay here.
I threaten best alone.
Hey! You. uh. seen
a Federation ship around here?
Seems like it's going well.
Ooh!
Still might be going well.
We don't know what he's into.
Maybe he likes that.
He tell you where it is?
They were weak.
didn't know how to negotiate.
So now I'm their leader.
Okay. And that means
you know where the shuttle is?
I do. But what will you give me?
What do you mean "give you"?
Well. I need something
in return.
They were ready
to just hand it over.
Good! They should hand it over.
I told them to up their game.
So now I need to show them
how it's done.
Give me your shirt.
-My shirt? No.
-Give me your shirt.
Give her your shirt.
I'll say it has some kind of
deep Earth meaning.
It does have a deep Earth
meaning. it's my favorite shirt.
Uncalled for.
-And now I'm chilly.
-Victory!
Okay. so. they found the shuttle
hidden behind a billboard.
Couldn't sell it
because it's damaged
and the operating chip
is missing.
Can you fix this?
We can use it to find the chip.
Yeah.
My tools are right...
That is odd.
Why are they out?
Oh.
No. I think it makes sense.
You got the chip
from the attendant.
Which means you came here...
-Wait.
-tried to fix the shuttle
because you are the king
of micromanaging.
And were so drunk you broke it.
hid the shuttle
to cover your mistake.
and totally screwed us over?
Scanning in progress.
Shuttle Seven-E
operating component
is eight centimeters away.
It's in here.
20 centimeters away.
What did you do?
Did you move it?
I didn't touch anything.
11 centimeters away.
0.3 centimeters away.
You gotta be kidding.
-Help me with this cast.
-Uh...
The duotronic processing chip.
You had it.
Had it... Have... Had it.
The whole time.
There has to be an explanation.
Yeah. I think the explanation
is that you're really...
Ow!
They stole my eyeballs!
We've got bags on our heads.
C-Can you reach my hands?
Untie me.
My eyeballs are still here.
Here. here. move sideways.
maybe I can get you.
Why aren't you yelling at me?
Yelling just to yell?
Like an "argh" kind of thing?
Yelling because
I've been blaming you for
losing the shuttle.
but apparently it was me.
You just accepted
that you did it.
Get your foot out of my face.
No. that I will not
take the blame for.
You moved your face to my foot.
It's 'cause I grew up
with six brothers.
Bet your house smelled great.
When things went wrong.
I got the blame.
and they usually
were my fault. so...
Suppose I just assume
it's still that way now.
I didn't know you had brothers.
Hard to picture seven of you.
Four adopted.
Mom used to say
that hearts are infinite.
so we should
make use of that space.
Mine said something
not too different.
Okay. come on. Let's try again.
Oh. hang on! Hang on!
I've almost got a grip.
I used to get in trouble
for blaming Beto
for things that weren't
entirely his fault.
You mean your fault?
Maybe all we needed to do
was compromise.
Work together! Oh...
I thought maybe
we'd say the same thing.
-Dendru!
-Please...
check your fisticuffs
at the door.
I only did what you both asked...
what you both begged me to do.
Why would we want to be
kidnapped?
My journey is to do
whatever I can
to keep guests on their journey.
My job is not to ask questions.
Why would we
want to be kidnapped?
-My journey is to do whatever...
-I just asked that same question.
I don't mind repeating it.
What exactly
did we ask you to do?
"Dendru. no matter what.
"keep us away from our shuttle.
Tie us up if you have to."
That does sound like me.
And then we sealed the deal
with what you called
"big-up high-fives."
Those are fun.
Yes!
Yeah. I'm gonna need
more than that.
No. it's okay. we have the chip.
we have the shuttle.
We can go find
the captain and leave.
-Like. we did it.
-But we're missing something!
-Don't you see that?
-Still so angry.
I hoped your journey
would help you with that.
Wait. did you plan this?
You purposely gave me...
us... that note to deliver?
When the message came in.
it seemed like a good thing
for you to focus on.
instead of your frustrations.
This has been a terrible trip.
You are a terrible
puppet master.
I used to be a lot like you.
Oh. I doubt it. smiley.
I'm sorry that
my plan didn't work.
Because I do know how it feels
to always be looking
for something to be angry about.
If you look hard enough.
you'll always find
some reason to be mad.
You just need to decide
if you're going to ignore it.
or let it ruin your day.
or... or perhaps.
try to figure out what it is
you're really angry about.
We should... we need to go.
You may want to stop by
Room C on your way.
Apparently.
one of your crewmates
is causing an issue.
G-47.
We have G-47.
Bingo! Bingo. bingo. bingo!
In your face. Leoda!
You might as well just
give me your firstborn
-'cause I am coming for it!
-Not who I expected.
All right.
I think you've had enough.
She can't leave yet!
I've gotta win my money back.
Not my fault
you can't cut it. Cornelia!
This has gone on long enough.
Now we play by our rules.
Oh! Show me what you got!
Oh. no. let's not show anything.
Let's just show leaving.
Heard rumors something ugly's
going down in here.
Fight club!
We have to go.
The captain is waiting.
-We need you.
-Avenge me!
B-1. We have B-1.
Oh. hey. We sure hope
you'll come visit us again soon.
Be sure you have
all of your belongings.
including anyone you came with.
and no one extra.
She'll stay afloat
long enough to get us home.
After that...
Okay. guys.
No matter what.
this has to go well.
We are Starfleet officers.
and as of right now.
we are back on duty.
Even if the world is on fire.
no interruptions.
There's too much at stake.
A steak sounds really good
right now. doesn't it?
-Yes. sir.
-Why is that?
I don't think
the atmospheric effects
have left our system yet.
Yeah. I kind of picked up
on that.
I guess they said it
affects everyone differently.
It's so bright.
Formal hello.
I am Co'Rah.
I'm USS Christopher Pike.
Formal welcome.
We were surprised you requested
the talks be pulled forward.
Though we appreciate
your dedication to the matter.
I do not recall
making this request.
Such a you thing to do though.
Is something amiss?
You are making strange sounds.
Me?
Everything's peachy.
Formal peachy.
Er... why are you here?
Came to fix the shuttle.
Figured it's the least
I could do.
-You?
-Same.
Thanks.
I can't stop thinking. like.
why would you and I together
ask to be kept apart
from the shuttle?
Like. what were we even
doing together?
Good point.
Remember earlier how I said
I used to blame Beto
for things that weren't...
fully his fault?
Things that were your fault.
Let me get this out.
The reason is that I was...
maybe jealous.
He's a natural at everything.
and I think I wanted to see
something be hard
for someone besides me.
You know I failed
Impulse Mechanics?
The intro course.
I joined the Academy
to be an engineer.
but I never had the head
for intermix chambers. I guess.
Luckily. I had a head
for flying.
Well. intermix chambers
are overrated.
I've been so angry
at you lately.
and it's not even you
I'm mad at.
It's just the idea of me
not being good enough.
When you pointed out
that my flying could be better.
it just...
set me off.
Fun fact.
I usually avoid the helm.
That's why it was hard
to picture myself
stealing the shuttle.
I once crashed one.
Well. actually seven.
It was during my only
piloting class.
I couldn't cut it.
and maybe I'm a bit...
envious of anyone who did.
It's easy to get mad
at people who seem...
better than me.
Blame them for things.
try to bring them down a peg.
I guess like my brothers
did to me. you know?
That's a lot
of crashed shuttles.
Oh. so. so many shuttles.
Luckily.
I had a head for engineering.
-I guess we're...
-Not so different after all?
I was going to say
a couple of screwups
who found our callings.
but yeah.
Your thing. too.
Yeah.
Oh. what's this?
Wait. what is this?
-What is this? What is this?
-Oh. sh...
-Bomb.
This is... this is...
Just... let's get it
deactivated.
This is reactive bomb casing.
Is that exactly
what it sounds like?
If I move my hands.
it's going to... well. you know.
Any idea how big
that "you know" might be?
Well. I'd rather
not find out. Um...
I'm gonna go get help.
You are joking me.
Conflict is
the infancy of progress.
instrumental
in creating a harmony.
And though our differences
in belief
may seem immutable.
sovereignties are dedicated
to negotiating conflicts
through diplomacy. right?
And this remains true...
this is for our alleyways...
There is a bomb on board.
Red alert.
I don't know how big.
Tell the captain.
Important.
Where did I put that?
-Okay.
-Whether or not
there is a democracy of voices...
which. frankly.
I think there are.
Lieutenant.
I heard about the avocado.
-What?
-The message you gave
to Uhura.
which she passed down the line.
"Palm. avocado bad.
tell captain"?
I should've known
that wouldn't work.
Using reverse human logic.
I deduced that you may have
been referring
to a bomb on board.
Or just bad avocados.
Either way. I am here to help.
I should warn you. however.
you are still a plant.
Pull it together. man.
We need you.
Indeed. a highly
sensitive reactive casing.
Was it attached
to a power source?
Self-powered.
It was in there.
One of our isolinear
recording chips?
-Has this been scanned?
-We didn't see it.
Kinda dealing with other things.
-Okay. this message is for...
-Us.
Future us.
Which means... hey... you.
-You guys are smart.
-Mm-hmm.
You'll figure out
what's going on.
-They... we...
-Right?
definitely will.
We each came back
to fix the shuttle!
-Shut up. man. What?
-Just let me talk.
Let me talk. let me talk.
Uh. we found out someone
tampered with the shuttle.
Shuttle's a funny word.
"Shuttle." Oh. yeah. yeah.
Someone messed with the shuttle.
Mm-hmm.
Maybe to ruin the peace talks?
Maybe to be a big jerk.
We don't know what they did yet.
But we're going to hide the
"shushle" until we find Pike.
just to make sure no one uses it
for. like. bad-guy reasons.
I hid the chip
in this fake cast.
In case this place makes us
forget what we're doing.
Oh. future us. no matter what.
do not bring the shuttle back
to the Enterprise
until we... well. you...
figure this out.
Let's go!
Yep. seems like past us could
have come up with a better plan.
It is indeed not very logical.
Okay. plant boy. just help.
The bomb is comprised
of Quadrium particles...
rare. once native
to the Rodaxian system.
combined with
Varuvian and Nitrilin.
The scale of the explosion
would be catastrophic.
Can we transport it off?
This combination
is too volatile.
That would initiate the bomb.
-The captain?
-After I left
the mess hall.
he locked the room.
Then I'll break the door down!
-We have to do something.
-There is too little time.
-Jettison the shuttle.
-That will not help.
As soon as you let go.
the bomb will explode.
-Yeah. I won't let go.
-You can't do that. You'll die.
We have no choice.
Enough talking. just get off
this shuttle and let me go.
You can't fly it. Both
your hands are on that bomb.
I'll work it out.
I'm going with you.
Spock. leave.
We're doing this.
I will attempt to transport you
out at the moment of detonation.
A zeptosecond before explosion.
It would certainly be easier
with another set of hands.
On it.
It is worse than I thought.
I am still hallucinating.
We'll deal with that later.
I got the gist. but brief me.
If only you were real.
I could use assistance
-now more than ever.
-Spock...
I must concentrate.
Hallucination. begone.
Was that imaginary?
No. because it hurt.
Didn't it?
-You want another?
-I do not.
Good.
Now let's save this ship.
and our friends.
Recalibrate emitter array
to compensate
for Quadrium radiation variables
in biofilter assembly.
Got it.
I think it's happening.
It's getting hotter. Very hot.
Ortegas to Spock. This is it.
Scotty...
It's okay. I'm...
I think we would have
been friends.
I think we already are.
Formal I'm sorry.
That was an insulting affront
to our formal
cultural traditions.
history. and every principle
these negotiations stand...
Wow.
-Are we...
-The afterlife
looks surprisingly
like the Enterprise.
I think we're alive.
You are indeed alive.
-We're alive!
The Ancient Rodaxian
Formal Rite of Peace
has not been seen
in generations.
The danger and expense
and effort
you must have put
into obtaining Quadrium.
and invoking this...
you've deeply honored us today.
Let the peace talks now begin.
In hopes of leaving
as one planet.
-You guys.
-All right.
Bring it in.
I think I'm sobering up.
Did we really just
come that close to dying?
That was really. really close.
I was holding on
to the bomb... Oh!
This really. really hurts now!
Oh. just... okay. just...
Oh. my God.
Don't look at it.
How can I not look at
it? It's looking right at me!
Before you fade away.
I must tell you.
I have enjoyed
our time together.
Even though it
was definitely not...
We're going to sickbay!
Oh. hey. Kirk.
-It's a paper cut.
-No. it's not!
real.
They saw you.
Spock. I'm not gonna fade away.
I mean. at some point I'll leave
to go back to my ship.
but you're not imagining me.
Then why would you be here?
Oh. well. I was
on vacation on Cesnar.
I'm glad I ran into you.
It was nice to get
to know you better.
A mind meld
only takes you so far.
I told you everything.
-Everything.
-You sure did.
And those many.
many secrets are safe with me.
Are you going to hug me again?
Do you want me to?
Okay. highlights.
-You two...
-I don't want to hear it.
Running into that costume party
trying to talk to Pike
and having to put on
those loaner costumes.
Oh. I can't even think about how
many people wore that before me.
Though that does explain
why I still smell it.
-Gross. dude.
-Why we all still smell it.
I will forever regret
missing your party.
Appropriate.
We weren't invited.
I still don't understand
what happened though.
Spock said I "got the dragon."
-The "dragon bomb."
-What?
You knocked over something
Dendru called a "dragon bomb."
It was supposed to be
a relaxing airborne vapor.
-enough for the whole club.
-But you two
may have inhaled
the whole thing.
That explains a lot.
-Good news.
-Hey!
The saboteur
has been apprehended.
Some Rodaxian militant
that would clearly do anything
to stop the negotiations.
Including plotting to blow up
leaders from both factions.
while they were
aboard the Enterprise.
Chris. you have something...
Doc. could you remove these. please?
Hmm.
-Hey. there he is!
-Excuse me.
All right. nimble fingers.
Doctor.
Wow!
Yes. to help with
the decision-making.
Thank you. sir.
Hey. what do you guys think
about maybe making this. like.
-like an annual crew trip?
-Mm-mm.
Yeah. if I can wear
that dress again.
-Come on. dude.
-Yeah.
Does anyone want
to see my tattoo?
No.
There we go!
Personal log. supplemental.
We're back in the rocky
area of space...
which. as any pilot knows...
sometimes you gotta
push your way forward.
But sometimes
you just need
to get out of your own way.
Don't tell me this is all from
pushing the thrusters a little?
I wasn't exaggerating.
Here. hand me that cell.
Guess I could ease
into it a little more.
instead of punching.
Come on.
I'm actually working
to reroute the way power
is distributed through the...
oh. your favorite.
the intermix chamber.
That might allow you
a wee bit more push.
But. you know. just a wee bit.
Okay?
Deal.
And I won't let you down.
I know you won't.
Oh. we should have
started it like this.
-Let's do it again.
Let's do it again.
Perfect.
-Nailed it.
-Mm-hmm.
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org